ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers, 5780/088
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II. ILGWU Administration Files, 1955-1982
  - Calendar (ILGWU events only), 1973-1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    10/73-12/81.
  - Central States Region, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    1/68- 10/69. Mainly correspondence with Vice President Fred Siems and disgruntled members.
  - Central States Region, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    10/69- 12/70.
  - Central States Region, 1971-1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    2/71- 1/81.
  - Sol C. Chaikin, 1974-1978 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    9/74-4/78. Correspondence with, and on behalf of, President - General Secretary-Treasurer Chaikin about various issues (mainly education and politics).
  - Sol C. Chaikin, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    4/78-7/78.
  - Sol C. Chaikin, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    7/78-1/79.
  - Sol C. Chaikin, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Sol C. Chaikin, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    6/79-3/80.
  - Sol C. Chaikin, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    3/80-8/80.
  - Sol C. Chaikin, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    9/80-11/80.
  - Sol C. Chaikin, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    11/80-3/81.
  - Sol C. Chaikin, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    3/81-6/81.
  - Sol C. Chaikin, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    7/81-12/81.
  - Citizens Committee for a Constitutional Convention, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    7/65-3/66.
  - Cloak Joint Board. [folder 1 of 2], 1967-1972 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    10/67-10/72. Mainly correspondence with Vice President Henoch Mendelsund and disgruntled members.
  - Cloak Joint Board. [folder 2 of 2], 1967-1972 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Cloak Out-of-Town Department, 1968-1972 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    3/68-10/72. Mainly correspondence with Vice President Henoch Mendelsund, Mildred Lippman, and disgruntled members.
  - Contractor control, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    Clause in 1965 Bobbie Brooks contract.
  - 1965 ILGWU Convention (Box 23, Folder 1)
    7/65.
  - 1974 ILGWU Conference (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - 1977 ILGWU Convention (Box 23, Folder 3)
    4/77-5/77? Report of Education Department.
  - 1980 ILGWU Convention (Box 23, Folder 4)
    1/80-10/80. Report of Education Department.
  - Cotton City, 1964 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    11/64. Contract negotiations.
  - Wilbur Daniels, 1970-1982 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    3/70-7/82. Miscellaneous correspondence.
  - Dress Joint Board, 1968-1969 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    2/68-9/69. Mainly correspondence with Vice Presidents Charles Zimmerman and Israel Breslow, and disgruntled members.
  - Dress Joint Board, 1969-1971 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    12/69- 5/71.
  - Dress Joint Board, 1971-1972 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    5/71- 12/72.
  - East Bronx Community Festival (Box 23, Folder 10)
    Undated.
  - Eastern Region, 1963-1970 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    9/63-1/70. Mainly correspondence with Vice President Edward Kramer and disgruntled members.
  - Eastern Region, 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    2/70-7/71.
  - Eastern Region, 1971-1979 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    11/71-8/79.
  - Education Department, 1968-1972 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    9/68-3/72.
  - Fashion Apparel Manufacturers Association, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    7/65-9/65.
  - Federation of Union Representatives (FOUR), 1962-1967 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    8/62?-9/67. Concerns attempt to form union of ILGWU organizers, staff, and business agents.
  - First Aid and Blood Bank, 1976-1979 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    3/76-4/79. Relates to training union members in first aid and CPR. Also concerns members' blood donations.
  - Foundations Group, 1969-1975 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    2/69- 12/75. Philanthropy organization including the Dubinsky Foundation.
  - General Executive Board Committee on Education, 1968-1970 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    10/68-1/70. Reports from Education Department.
  - Genesco. Organizing literature from campaign at Formfit Plaza plant, 1965-1966 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    10/65-1/66.
  - Genesco. Organizing literature from campaign at Hobco plant in Hobson, Alabama, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    3/66.
  - Genesco. Newspaper clippings and research, 1964-1965 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    2/64-11/65.
  - Heckler Corporation, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    10/65. Contract negotiations.
  - Immigration, 1964-1965 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    10/64-5/65.
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union. Archives, 1976-1978 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    11/76-4/78.
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union. General Executive Board Meeting Notices, 1971- 1976 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    1/71-7/76.
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union. History, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    3/67.
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union. Scholarship Fund, 1969-1971 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    2/69-10/71.
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union. Staff Training Institute, 1966-1969 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    3/66-9/69.
  - International Women's Conference, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    7/77. The New York State Women's Conference in Albany
  - Jack Barnes, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    8/65. Contract negotiations - Problems and Solutions for Local 91
  - Jesse Miller Company, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    12/65. Contract negotiations. Includes Health and Welfare Fund Report.
  - Job Applications, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    10/77-1/78. File of resumes of college graduates looking for staff positions with the ILGWU. Contains an essay called "Jewish Self-Defense."
  - Job Applications, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    1/78-6/78.
  - Job Applications, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    6/78-1/79.
  - Job Applications, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    1/79-9/79.
  - Job Applications, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    9/79-3/80.
  - Job Applications, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Job Applications, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    7/80-1/81.
  - Job Applications, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    2/81-8/81.
  - Job Applications, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    8/81-11/81.
  - Job Applications sent to Executive Vice President Frederick Siems, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    3/78-4/78.
  - Jonathan Logan, 1963-1966 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    12/63-1/66. Contract negotiations. Includes a pension plan and newspaper clippings.
  - Judy Bond, 1963-1967 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    10/63-2/67. Concerns strike, public boycott campaign, and dispute with the United Garment Workers of America.
  - John F. Kennedy Memoriam, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Labor Education and Policy Associates (LEAP), 1979 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    11/79.
  - Lortogs, Incorporated, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    12/64. Newspaper clippings.
  - Maidenform, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    3/63-9/65. Contract negotiations.
  - Manpower Development and Training Act, 1964-1966 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    2/64-6/66.
  - Master Contract Correspondence, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    6/65-9/65.
  - Bill Mathews. Pennsylvania Education Director, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    5/65. Booklet used for classes with members.
  - Memo / For Staff Only, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    1/76- 1/77. ILGWU publication.
  - Mendelsund Project, 1971-1973 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    1/71- 11/73. Course in labor-management relations at Fashion Institute of Technology, designed by Professor Jack Barbash of the University of Wisconsin.
  - Mendelsund Project, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    11/73- 11/74.
  - Midwest Department. [folder 1 of 2], 1968-1972 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    2/68-9/72. Mainly correspondence with Vice President Morris Bialis and disgruntled members.
  - Midwest Department. [folder 2 of 2], 1968-1972 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Minimum Wage Legislation. [folder 1 of 2], 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    12/63-12/65. Statements, testimonies, newspaper clippings.
  - Minimum Wage Legislation. [folder 2 of 2], 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Montreal Joint Board, 1964-1972 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    1/64- 4/72. Mainly correspondence with Vice Presidents Bernard Shane and Si Bresner, and disgruntled members. Newspaper included.
  - New England Region, 1977-1981 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    7/77- 4/81. Mainly correspondence with Vice President Edward Milano.
  - New York City Central Labor Council, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - New York City Locals, 1963-1969 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    9/63- 1/69. Mainly correspondence with Vice Presidents Ed Schneider, Matthew Schoenwald, E. Howard Molisani, Louis Nelson, Sol Greene, Douglas Levin, and disgruntled members.
  - New York City Locals, 1969-1971 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    1/69- 6/71.
  - New York City Locals, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    6/71-12/71.
  - New York City Locals, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    12/71- 9/72.
  - New York State 1967 Constitutional Convention. [folder 1 of 2], 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    11/65-7/67.
  - New York State 1967 Constitutional Convention. [folder 2 of 2], 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Non-union contractors, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    3/66. Report to President Dubinsky.
  - Northeast Department, 1967-1969 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    3/67- 4/69. Mainly correspondence with Vice President Sol C. Chaikin and disgruntled members.
  - Northeast Department, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    4/69-11/69.
  - Northeast Department, 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    12/69-7/70.
  - Northeast Department, 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    7/70-1/71.
  - Northeast Department, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    1/71-3/71.
  - Northeast Department, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    3/71-1/72.
  - Northeast Department, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    1/72-5/72.
  - Northeast Department, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    5/72-3/73.
  - Ohio. Kentucky Region, 1969-1972 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    4/69-4/72. Mainly correspondence with Vice President Sam Janis and disgruntled members.
  - Organizing. [folder 1 of 2], 1977-1980 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    7/77-1/80. Concerns ILGWU organizing activity. Includes material from George Meany Center for Labor Studies Institute on Organizing, 1977 ILGWU Organizing Conference, and correspondence with Executive Vice President Frederick Siems.
  - Organizing. [folder 2 of 2], 1977-1980 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Pacific Coast Office / Western States Region, 1968-1972 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    1/68-10/72. Mainly correspondence with Vice Presidents Samuel Otto and Cornelius Wall, and disgruntled members.
  - Frank Pagan, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    7/69-8/69.
  - Paperback Service. [folder 1 of 2], 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    4/64-11/66. Program run by Education Department to order books for members at discount prices.
  - Paperback Service. [folder 2 of 2], 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Perfect Garment Company, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    11/65-2/66. Contract negotiations.
  - Jasper Peyton, 1969-1972 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    10/69-1/72. Assistant Education Director.
  - Philadelphia Dress Joint Board, 1966-1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    1/66-3/70. Mainly correspondence with Vice President William Ross and disgruntled members.
  - Philadelphia Dress Joint Board, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    5/70-8/70.
  - Philadelphia Dress Joint Board, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    8/70-9/72.
  - Price Watch, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    3/79-6/79. Anti-inflation program run by Education Department. Involves monitoring of consumer prices by union members.
  - Puerto Rican Minimum Wage, 1955-1966 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    5/55-4/66. Newspaper, newspaper clippings, general correspondence.
  - Puerto Rican Minimum Wage, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    4/66-5/66. Newspaper clippings and general correspondence.
  - Puerto Rican Minimum Wage, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    5/66-6/66.
  - Puerto Rico Local 600-601, 1967-1980 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    1/67-4/80. Mainly correspondence with Vice Presidents Alberto Sanchez, Clifford W. Depin, and Manuel Gonzalez.
  - Puritan Fashions Corporation, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    1/64-12/65. Contract negotiations and newspaper clippings.
  - Retiree Programs, 1979-1981 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    9/79- 1/81.
  - Rhoda Lee, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    3/63. Company mislabeling of imported blouses.
  - Saul Rosen, 1978-1981 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    6/78-7/81. Associate Education Director. This folder includes the book called "Dissent."
  - Rosenau Brothers, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    2/65- 1/66. Contract negotiations.
  - Russ Togs, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    12/64-9/65. Newspaper clippings.
  - Frederick Siems, 1977-1982 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    10/77- 6/82. Correspondence with Executive Vice President Siems, mainly on organizing.
  - Slate Belt Contractors Association, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    1/64-2/65. Newspaper clippings.
  - Social Security, 1965-1967 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    12/65-3/67. Statements and opinions on benefit increases.
  - South Jersey. Philadelphia Joint Board, 1968-1970 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    1/68-7/70. Mainly correspondence with Manager Harry Benn and disgruntled members.
  - Southeast Department, 1967-1969 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    10/67-5/69. Mainly correspondence with Vice Presidents Martin Morand and Nicholas Bonanno, and disgruntled members.
  - Southeast Department, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    6/69-4/70.
  - Southeast Department, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    7/70-4/71.
  - Southeast Department, 1971-1979 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    4/71-5/79.
  - Sportswear and Allied Workers Joint Board, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    ?-9/79.
  - Scholarship, Training, Education, and Politics (STEP), 1969-1972 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    1/69-1/72. Bimonthly publication of the departments of Scholarship, Training, Education, and Politics.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1963-1966 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    9/63-5/66. Correspondence with, and on behalf of, President - General Secretary-Treasurer Stulberg.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    5/66-8/66.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    8/66-12/66.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    12/66-5/67.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    5/67-10/67.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    10/67-4/68. [Includes 8x10 photograph of Stulberg at his desk.]
  - Louis Stulberg, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    4/68-12/68.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    1/69-6/69.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    6/69-11/69.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    11/69-2/70.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    2/70-4/70.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    4/70-1/71.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    1/71-2/71.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    2/71-5/71.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    5/71-10/71.
  - Louis Stulberg, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    10/71-12/71.
  - Style Undies, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    8/65. Research.
  - Tax Proposals (New York City), 1966 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    3/66-5/66.
  - Union Counselor's Manual, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    8/74.
  - Union Health Center, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    8/80-11/80. Mainly correspondence with George Bailey (Director of Social Services).
  - Union Label Department, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    12/65-2/66. Correspondence with Min Matheson, John Denaro, and others about the union label publicity campaign. Includes materials on strategy, planning, and media use.
  - Union Label Department, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    2/66-5/66.
  - Union Label Department, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    5/66-9/66.
  - Union Label Department, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    9/66-11/66.
  - Union Label Department, 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    11/66-1/67.
  - Union Label Department, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    1/67-4/67.
  - Union Label Department, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    4/67-7/67.
  - Union Label Department, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    8/67-5/68.
  - Union Label Department, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    5/68-4/69.
  - Union Label Department, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    5/69-1/70.
  - Union Label Department, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    1/70-4/70.
  - Union Label Department, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    4/70-7/70.
  - Union Label Department, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    8/70-11/70.
  - Union Label Department, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    11/70-5/71.
  - Union Label Department, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    5/71-12/71.
  - Union Label Department, 1971-1979 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    12/71-1/79.
  - Unity House, 1975-1980 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    9/75-2/80.
  - Upper South Department, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    1/68-1/69. Mainly correspondence with Vice Presidents Sol Hoffman and Angela Bambace, and disgruntled members.
  - Upper South Department. [folder 1 of 2], 1969-1972 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    1/69-10/72.
  - Upper South Department. [folder 2 of 2], 1969-1972 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Wentworth Manufacturing Company, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    1/65-6/65. Contract negotiations and newspaper clippings.
- Series III. ILGWU Political Activity, 1956-1981
  Contains files on local and national politics relevant to Tyler's office of ILGWU Political Director. Primary subjects are imports, the Liberal Party, and the 1969 New York City mayoral election.
  - Murray Baron, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    4/68-6/68. 1968 Senatorial candidate in Liberal Party primary, backed by ILGWU. Includes various newspaper clippings.
  - Burke-Hartke Bill. Congressional responses to ILGWU's position from California, Utah, Arizona, Washington, and Minnesota, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    1/73-9/73. The bill proposed across-the-board quotas on imports and had the backing of the ILGWU.
  - Burke-Hartke Bill. Congressional responses to ILGWU's position from Ohio, Kentucky, Arkansas, Indiana, and Montana, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    1/73-2/73.
  - Burke-Hartke Bill. Congressional responses to ILGWU's position from New York, New Jersey, Maine, Pennsylvania, and Connecticut, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    10/72-5/73.
  - Burke-Hartke Bill. Congressional responses to ILGWU's position from Special Committee members, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    1/73-5/73.
  - Burke-Hartke Bill. Congressional responses to ILGWU's position from Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina, Florida, West Virginia, and South Dakota, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    12/72-1/73.
  - Burke-Hartke Bill. Summary of congressional responses to Stulberg's letter. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Burke-Hartke Bill. Newspaper clippings detailing House Ways and Means Chairman Wilbur Mills' views on trade, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    3/73.
  - Burke-Hartke Bill. Pre-Easter picketing. Advertising ideas (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Burke-Hartke Bill. Pre-Easter picketing. Costs, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    3/73- 5/73.
  - Burke-Hartke Bill. Pre-Easter picketing. General Correspondence, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    2/73-4/73. Includes photographs of pickets.
  - Burke-Hartke Bill. Pre-Easter picketing. Instructions for picketing and petitioning, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    1/73-4/73.
  - Burke-Hartke Bill. Pre-Easter picketing. Orders for shopping bags, literature, picket signs, etc., 1972- 1973 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    10/72-4/73.
  - 1948, 1952, and 1954 Campaign Committees (Box 14, Folder 17)
    Undated. Leaflets.
  - 1956 Campaign Committee (Box 14, Folder 18)
    7/56-11/56.
  - 1958 Campaign Committee, 1958-1959 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    7/58-8/59.
  - 1960 Campaign Committee. [folder 1 of 2], 1960-1961 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    2/60-8/61.
  - 1960 Campaign Committee. [folder 2 of 2], 1960-1961 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - 1962 Campaign Committee (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Campaign Committee (Box 14, Folder 23)
    Undated. Poster
  - Carter campaign and administration, 1976-1980 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    3/76-3/80.
  - Committee on Political Education (COPE), 1979-1981 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    12/79-10/81. Notices of meetings and correspondence.
  - Congress, 1979-1981 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    6/79-10/81. General correspondence with senators and representatives.
  - Democratic Party Platform Committee, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    2/80-6/80. Tyler's testimony.
  - General correspondence about political issues, 1964-1968 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    9/64-3/68.
  - General correspondence about political issues, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    3/68- 4/68.
  - General correspondence about political issues, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    4/68- 8/68.
  - General correspondence about political issues, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    8/68- 12/68.
  - General correspondence about political issues, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    1/69- 10/69.
  - General correspondence about political issues, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    10/69- 12/69.
  - General correspondence about political issues, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    1/70- 6/70.
  - General correspondence about political issues, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    6/70- 10/70.
  - Liberal Party. General correspondence and newspaper articles, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Liberal Party. General correspondence and newspaper articles, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    1/68-4/68.
  - Liberal Party. General correspondence and newspaper articles, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    4/68-8/68.
  - Liberal Party. General correspondence and newspaper articles, 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    8/68-3/70.
  - Liberal Party. General correspondence and newspaper articles, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    3/70-5/70.
  - Liberal Party. General correspondence and newspaper articles, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    6/70-6/71.
  - Liberal Party. Correspondence, newspaper articles, and columns about 1969 New York City mayoral election (Box 15, Folder 7)
    2/69-6/69.
  - Liberal Party. Correspondence, newspaper articles, and columns about 1969 New York City mayoral election (Box 15, Folder 8)
    6/69-7/69.
  - Liberal Party. Correspondence, newspaper articles, and columns about 1969 New York City mayoral election (Box 15, Folder 9)
    7/69-10/69.
  - Liberal Party. Correspondence, newspaper articles, and columns about 1969 New York City mayoral election (Box 15, Folder 10)
    10/69-11/69.
  - Liberal Party. Correspondence, newspaper articles, and columns about 1969 New York City mayoral election (Box 15, Folder 11)
    11/69.
  - Liberal Party. Correspondence, newspaper articles, and columns about 1969 New York City mayoral election (Box 15, Folder 12)
    11/69-12/69.
  - New York City 1969 Democratic mayoral primary (Box 15, Folder 13)
    5/69- 8/69. Details ILGWU's efforts on behalf of Robert Wagner.
  - New York City politics, 1969-1978 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    3/69- 6/78.
  - Queens-Nassau County Liberal Party, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    7/68.
- Series IV. Speaking Engagements, 1963-1981
  Contains calendar dates and materials related to lectures and seminars given by Tyler to government agencies, companies, and non-profit institutions.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    10/63-7/64.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    7/64-1/65.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1965 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    1/65-4/65.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    4/65-2/66.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1966 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1966 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    4/66-7/66.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1966 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    7/66-11/66.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    11/66-3/67.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1967 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1967 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1967 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1967 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    6/67-8/67.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    8/67-1/68.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1968 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1968 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    4/68-6/68.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1968 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    6/68-10/68.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    10/68-1/69.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1969 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    2/69-4/69.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1969 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    4/69-9/69.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1969 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    9/69.
  - Speaking Engagements (General), 1969 (Box 16, Folder 15)